RG 051, Philadelphia Sesquicentennial Committee
Connecticut State Library
Governor's Sesqui-Centennial Committee records
1926-1927
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Governor's Sesqui-Centennial Committee
7 cubic feet
The Committee built, furnished, and operated a Connecticut building for the Philadelphia Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition. The building was modeled after the old state capitol, and equipped it with exhibits of Connecticut life and industry.
RG051
T002710
Historical Note
On April 1, 1926, Governor John Trumbull and the State Board of Control authorized Connecticut’s participation in the “Philadelphia Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition” celebrating the signing of the Declaration of Independence. Thirty-five thousand dollars was allocated, and a committee consisting of George S. Godard, State Librarian and Chairman, former Governor Frank B. Weeks, and State Treasurer Ernest E. Rogers were appointed. The Committee built, furnished, and operated a Connecticut building, modeled after the old state capitol, and equipped it with exhibits of Connecticut life and industry. At the end of the Exposition, the Committee sold the building, and held its last meeting on July 28, 1927.
Scope and Content
This record group contains minutes of meetings, an account book, pay receipts, registers of visitors, official town seals, blueprints of construction drawings and the contract for construction, ceremony programs and dinner menus, speeches and press releases, correspondence, and photographs of ceremonies, construction of the Connecticut building, and other sites at the Exposition.
Related Material
RG 005:025, John H. Trumbull gubernatorial records, Box 319, Philadelphia Sequi-Centennial Celebration
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Governor's Sesqui-Centennial Committee
Persons:
Trumbull, John Harper, 1873-1961; Godard, George S. (George Seymour), 1865-1936; Rogers, Ernest E. (Ernest Elias), 1866-1945; Weeks, Frank B.
Subjects:
Connecticut. Governor's Sesqui-Centennial Committee -- Records and correspondence; Sesqui-Centennial International Exposition (1926: Philadelphia, Pa.); Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Exhibitions
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Registers (lists); Photographs; Receipts (financial records)
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records were kept by George Godard as Chairman of the Committee and transferred to the State Library.
Container List
- Records, 1926-1927
  - 1. Minutes, 1926 April 12-1927 July 28 (Box 1)
    Two complete sets.
  - 2. Account book, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
    Shows expenditures for construction, furnishing and operation of the building and for Committee expenses.
  - 3. Pay receipts, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
    Contains receipts in duplicate for wage payments of staff at the building.
  - 4. Official town seals, 1926 (Box 1)
    Contains letters from officials of most Connecticut towns bearing their official seals, as requested by the Committee.
  - 5. Miscellaneous items (Box 2)
    - List of "Data Relative to Connecticut Building" (Box 2)
    - Contract for construction, first payment voucher, etc. (Box 2)
    - Blueprints of construction drawings, C.H. Dresser and Son (Box 2)
    - Nathan Hale Day proclamation by Governor John Trumbull, 1926 September 22 (Box 2)
    - Ceremony programs and dinner menus, etc. (Box 2)
    - Certificates of award conferred by the Exposition on the State of Connecticut and the Committee members (Box 2)
    - Texts of speeches and press releases (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1926; 2 folders (Box 2)
      Found in Vault 11, December 10, 1973 and Picture Room, April 1976.
  - 6. Photographs, 1926
    - Photographs of the Connecticut Building and the opening ceremonies, 1 bound volume
    - Loose copies of glossy prints, most with no captions, of photos with the building, the groundbreaking and opening ceremonies and other Exposition scenes. (Box 3)
  - 7. Registers of visitors, 1926; 6 bound volumes + 4 leaflets
    Contains registers of visitors to the Connecticut Building.
    - 1926 June 14-August 16 (Volume Unnumbered volume)
    - 1926 August 17-September 7 (Volume Volume 2)
      Includes envelope containing loose signature sheets that are dated September 7-8, 1926.
    - 1926 September 9-October 1 (Volume Volume 4)
      Includes envelope containing photographs. Includes also loose signature sheets dated September 9, 1926.
    - 1926 October 1-21 (Volume Volume 3)
    - 1926 October 21-24, 4 leaflets
    - 1926 October 24-November 13 (Volume Volume 5)
    - 1926 November 13-30 (Volume Volume 6)